## Farzana Kazi

34C Bokhari Commercial Lane 7 Phase 6 Defence Housing Authority Karachi - 75500

Home: +92 21 35242645 Mobile: +92 322 2017166

Email: Farzana.kazi3@gmail.com

### **Objective**

Accomplished IT Professional looking for new challenges where I can apply my system designing and programming skills to contribute to an organization to achieve its goals.

### **Summary**

Nearly 24 years of experience in the Information Technology, expertise in Information Systems software development, programming, user support. Implementation of packaged software, expertise in user support for SharePoint. A broad understanding of computer hardware and software, including installation, configuration, management, troubleshooting and support.

## **Professional Experience**

1. Site ERP Lead: 18<sup>th</sup> February 1989 to 30<sup>th</sup> June 2010 - Ciba-Geigy Pakistan Limited name changed to Novartis after merger with Sandoz & to Syngenta after de-merger of Plant protection business.

Worked initially as Programmer/ Analyst Programmer on IBM System/36 and later on AS/400 using RPG. The company initially Implemented BPCS (Business Planning & Control System) and developed an in-house Distribution System for Point of sale locations with complete integration with BPCS. I was part of the team which developed the Distribution System which included modules like Inventory Control, Order Processing, Invoicing, Accounts Receivable, Expense Monitoring etc.

The company implemented SAP in 2005. My responsibilities changed and I was nominated as the Site ERP lead and I was responsible for communication, logging and follow up of all SAP issues with our international consultants (Infosys), and was also responsible for user SAP access management.

In 2008 I was also given the assignment of "Lead Knowledge Advisor for the APAC (Asia and Australia) region" and was responsible for support of all country "Knowledge Advisor" and users training users and promoting use of team space in the company and represented APAC in the Global Knowledge Sharing Council.

I was also an Information Security Officer and Data Protection Officer for the company.

2. Trainee Programmer: January 1987 to February 1989 – Peat Marwick Associates: On job training for several clients using COBOL and RPG.

# **Education**

Karachi University (PECHS College) – Bachelors in ARTS (1984-85)

Grace Institute – Computer Comprehensive Course (1986)

During my stay in Syngenta Pakistan I attended a large number of professional & personnel development courses.

#### **Technical Skills**

Platforms: IBM/36, AS400

**Programming:** COBOL, RPG, Visual Basic. **Applications/Tools:** BPCS, SAP, MS Office.